嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的OpenGL系列教程
hey, what's up guys, my name is  TheCherno, and welcome back to my OpenGL series
那么我们已经在过去的几期中，过去的几周，过去的几个月里
so we've been over the last few episodes, over the last few weeks, over the last few months
我们学过的所有这些OpenGL基本概念
whatever we've been learning about all of these basic OpenGL concepts
现在我们真正拥有的是把这些概念放在一起的能力
and now what we actually have is the ability to like put all those concepts together
做一些更复杂的事情，并且那就是我们以后要讲到的
and actually do something a little bit more complicated, and that's where we're going to in the future
很快就会开始接触像批渲染和材质3D场景之类的东西
very soon start getting into things like batch rendering and materials 3D scenes that kind of stuff
并且为了促进那一点
and in order to facilitate that
我确实想花点时间，让它的应用变得有序
I really want to spend some time, and to actually get its application in order
因为就我们现在有的OpenGL应用而言
because what we have right now with our OpenGL application
它只是我们为这些东西创建了一堆接口类
it's really just all of we've got a bunch of api kind of classes that we've created for things
比如顶点缓冲区，顶点数组，索引缓冲区，纹理之类的东西
like vertex buffers, vertex arrays, index buffers, textures that kind of stuff
然后我们就有了这个Application.cpp文件
and then we've just got this Application.cpp file
也就是一些对OpenGL的调用
which is just kind of a bunch of just calls to OpenGL stuff
但我真正想做的是让我们有能力进行不同的测试
but what I really want to do is have the ability for us to have different tests
那么也就是说，不同的应用领域不同的场景
so to speak so different kind of areas of applications different scenes
我们可以在每一个测试或场景中循环
that we can actually cycle through and each one of those tests or scenes
是为了实际演示或者仅仅展示一个可行的概念
is meant to actually demonstrate or just show one concept working
所以基本上我想说的是，我希望我们能够有，比如这样一个场景
so basically what I'm saying is that I want us to be able to have, like a scene
只是一个批渲染的例子，这个场景只是一个非常非常简单的例子
that is just an example of batch rendering, a scene that is just an example of a very very simple
比如材质的使用或类似的东西，对吧
like material being used or something like that, right
一个像复杂着色器之类的场景
a scene that is like some complex shader or whatever
或者甚至只是一个简单的场景，就像，嘿
or even something that is just a scene that is as simple as, hey
这就是你们如何改变OpenGL的清除颜色
this is how you change the clear color at OpenGL
这就像一些我可以改变它的控制
and this is like some I'm going controls for being able to change that
这里就是渲染，对吧
here it is rendering, right
我想做的是创建一个不同概念的例子库
what I want to do is create like a library of examples of all of these different concepts
我们首先需要做的是创建一个能做到这些的应用程序
and what we need to kind of do first is to create an application that is capable of doing that
并且我们建立它的方法非常非常简单
and the way that we're going to set that up is very very simple
我们只是在ImGui中有一个菜单，显示所有可用的场景或测试或示例
we're just going to have a menu in ImGui, that shows all of the available scenes or tests or examples
并且我们将能够选择一个，当我们点击它时，它会打开相应的场景
and we're just going to be able to pick one, when we click it, it opens the scene
我们可以看到场景和所有与场景相关的图像控制
we can see the scene and all of the images controls that are associated with that scene there
然后我们可以点击返回按钮回到那个菜单，它基本上就会销毁那个场景
then we can click the return button to go back to that menu, and it will basically just destroy that scene
所以每次我们进入一个新场景时，它都会加载该场景所需的所有内容
so every time we go into a new scene, it loads everything required for that scene
并且当我们退出这个场景时，它会销毁一切东西
and when we exit the scene, it destroyed everything
所以如果我们一直进入退出，它会重新加载所有内容
so if we keep going back and forth, it reloads everything from scratch
并且那也表明所有的清理工作是没问题的
and that's also shows that all of that cleanup is working correctly
诸如此类的事情，好了，所以那就是我们的计划
and all of that kind of stuff, okay, so that's the plan
因为我真正想做的是，我得饮杯茶先
because what I actually thought about doing, I'm just gonna have to drink some tea first
我想做的只是像我上次说的那样进入批渲染
what I thought about doing was just getting into batch rendering like I said last time
和大多数人一样，我想，让你们选择材质或者批渲染
and most people, I think, and give you guys the choice of materials or batch rendering
你们选择了批渲染，这无疑是正确的选择
you went with batch rendering, which was the correct choice by the way
因为我本来也打算那做的，反正我必须坦白，不管如何
because that's what I would have done anyway, I must confess, anyway
所以我今天想做的不是这样做
so instead of doing that, which I would want to do that today
但我想，当我浏览这个主文件时，到处都是垃圾
but I thought like I look through this main file and there's so much junk everywhere
我基本上需要一个批渲染的例子，比如说一个整洁的文件
I want to basically have an example of batch rendering, a nice clean file
并且每一种文件都是一个类的实例
and every kind of file that is an example will be like an instance of a class
它将是一个类的实例，它实际上是一个单独的类
well it will be an instance of a class, it will literally be a separate class
它有onUpdate onRender onInit之类的函数
which just has like onUpdate onRender onInit, that kind of those kind of functions
因此，向你们展示如何设置批渲染的实际代码是尽可能少的
so that the actual code for showing you know how to set up batch rendering is as minimal as possible
并且那样的话，如果你们跟着做就会很简单
and that way, it's going to be really easy if you guys follow along
首先，如果你们没有当前的代码
first of all if you don't have the current code
你们可以在patreon.com/TheCherno上支持这个系列教程
you can do that by supporting this series on patreon.com/TheCherno
每一期代码都是作为一个单独的代码提交的
every single episode the code is committed as is committed as a separate commit to that
到github.com，比如TheCherno/OpenGL去访问获得那个
to github.com like TheCherno/OpenGL to get access to that
你们需要成为一个赞助人
you need to be a patron
这有助于支持这个系列，而且你们也可以获得每一集的提交
it helps support the series and also you get access to every single episode commit by commit
这是非常有用的，所以我们要从那个代码中继续
which is really useful, so that we're going to like continue on from that code
所以如果你们想继续下去而不需要把所有代码一个一个地敲
so if you want to follow along without having to type everything out
或者你们还没看过其他视频，那就是最好的方法
or you haven't watched the other episodes, that's the best way to do it
但我们要开始将这些代码重构到测试类中
but we're just going to start refraction this code out into test classes
这样我们就可以建立一个测试框架
so that we actually can set up a bit of a test framework
让所有这些都变得更容易，你们知道的
and facilitate all of that kind of, you know
我们从这个系列中学习的每个OpenGL概念的单独例子
separate examples of each OpenGL concept that we learn moving on from this series
让我们进入一些代码，讨论到此为止，看看我们能做些什么，好了
let's just jump into some code, enough talking, and see what we can do, okay
那么看一下这个应用程序类，它非常大，如果我现在运行我的代码
so looking through this application class, I mean it's pretty big, if I just run my code right now
这样我们就能看到我们让它开着的地方
so that we can see where we actually left this thing on
你们可以看到我们基本上只有两种像这样渲染的ChernoLogo
and you can see that we basically just have two kind of Cherno like this rendering
上一期我们讲了同时渲染多个东西
that was last episode where we talked about rendering multiple things at once
这是一个很好的例子，同样，在测试中用到它会很好
and we have all this is a great example, again, something that would be awesome to have in a test
但不是一些东西，我只是想在我们的主文件中
but not something, I just want to have in our main file
因为这把所有东西都弄乱了
because the clutters everything up
那么让我们开始考虑如何构建这个测试框架
so let's start thinking about how we want to make this test framework
我要做的第一件事是在这个src文件夹中
the first thing I want to do is inside this src folder
我要创建一个新项，实际上，我首先要创建一个新文件夹，就叫tests
I'm just going to make a new item, in fact, I'm just going to make a new folder first called tests
然后在里面，我要创建一个名为Test.h的文件
and then inside there, I'm gonna make a file called Test.h
我想，这将作为所有测试类的基类
and this is just gonna serve as the kind of base class I guess for all the test stuff
我还会把它放到一个名为test的命名空间中
I'm also gonna put it into a namespace called test
这样我们就能把它从实际的OpenGL中分离出来
just so that we can kind of have that isolated from the actual OpenGL and all that kind of stuff
然后我将它命名为Test类，我们将有很多公开的东西
and then I'm going to just call it class Test, and we're going to have a much public stuff
我不确定是否会有私有的东西，但基本上我们会有一个构造方法
I'm not sure if we'll have private stuff, but basically we're going to have a constructor
我把它留空，就像这样一个虚拟的析构方法，就像那样
which I'll just leave blank like this a virtual destruct over here, just like that
然后我将在这里创建一些虚函数，所以我们可能只需要OnUpdate
and then I'm going to make some virtual functions here, so we'll probably just have OnUpdate
理想情况下，帧速率是固定的，甚至可能需要一个deltaTime
which ideally would run at a fixed kind of frame rate, and maybe even take in a deltaTime here
然后我们还有一个OnRender，它是用来渲染的
and then we'll also have a OnRender, which is kind of meant for rendering
然后我会再做一个OnImGuiRender虚函数
and then I'm gonna actually make one more which is going to be and OnImGuiRender
所以这就是我们绘制ImGui东西的地方
so this is going to be where we're going to draw our ImGui stuff
所以理想情况下，我们要让它尽可能的简单
so ideally, we're going to make this as simple as possible
在这个函数中，我们重写了子类
so that in this function that we override in our subclasses
我们可以放任何我要渲染的代码
we can just put any kind of I'm going rendering code
它应该已经调用过了，就像我要开始了
and it would have already called, like I'm going to begin
对我们来说就是这样的东西，所以我们可以尽可能多
and that kind of stuff for us, so we can really just be as many as possible
我们不需要新建窗口之类的
in terms of like we don't need to make a new window or anything like that
它已经为我们设置好了从这个函数被调用的地方开始
it already be all set up for us from where this function actually gets called
所以那是基本的基础，现在我建立这个的方法是记住
so that's basically the basis of this, now the way I've set this up is remember
因为我希望所有这些测试类在进入测试时，都能被初始化或创建
because I actually want all these test classes to kind of be initialized or created, when we enter the test
然后销毁它，当我们退出测试时，实际的设置代码
and then destroy it, when we exit the test the actual setup code
创建和销毁代码会在构造方法和析构方法中
so the kind of creation and destruction code will be in the constructor and the destruct
这样我们就可以自由地使用任何类型的堆栈变量
so that way we can freely have any kind of stack variables
它们与类的生命周期密切相关的
that are kind of tied to the lifetime of our class
比如，如果我们想创建一个顶点缓冲区
like for example, if we wanted to create a vertex buffer
我们可以把它创建为堆栈变量就像在我们实际的类作用域中
we could just create that as a stack variable like in our actual class scope
并且那样的话，我们根本不需要担心手动处理内存管理
and that way, we don't have to worry about manual memory management at all
因为一旦这个类超出作用域一旦这个类被删除
because as soon as that class goes out of scope which as soon as that class gets deleted
堆栈上这个的顶点缓冲区会超出作用域
that the vertex buffer for this on the stack will get go out of scope
然后自动销毁，所以我们不用担心那个
and thus get destroyed automatically, so we don't have to worry about that
基本上，我想说的不是像onInit或OnDestroy这样的函数
basically what I'm saying is instead of having like an onInit or OnDestroy function
我只是有构造方法和析构方法
I'm just having construction and destruct
并且那样的话，类中所有对象的生存期实际上都绑定到类作用域
and that way, lifetime of all of our objects in the class is actually tied to the class scope
好了，不管怎样，那就是我们现有的，现在我们可以开始做一个测试了
okay, so anyway, that's basically what we have here, and now we can actually start making a test
那么举个例子，让我们来做一个我说过的清除颜色测试
so as an example, let's make that clear color test that I talked about
所以我要创建一个头文件，叫做TestClearColor
so I'm going to make a header file, which is just called TestClearColor
我将从单词Test开始，那样它们就井然有序了
I'm going to start them with the word test, that way they're nicely kind of ordered
我们将直接点击添加，我将对cpp文件做同样的事情
we'll head add, and I'll do the exact same thing for a cpp file
它叫做TestClearColor.cpp，它会包含我们的TestClearColor.h
it's all called TestClearColor.cpp, it's going to include our TestClearColor.h
并且在首行中，我将包含Test.h，那么再说一下，就是这个基础Test
and in the headline, I'm going to include just Test.h, so again next, base test
然后类TestClearColor，它会是，我们可能不需要
and then class TestClearColor, and it's going to be, we probably don't need to
也许我会叫它TestClearColor，只是因为我想要这个类的名字很好
maybe I will call a TestClearColor, just because I want the class as nicely named
但很明显，不管如何，这是一个测试
but it's pretty obvious that it's a test anyway
然后在这里，我们基本上要重写所有的东西
and then over here, we're going to basically override everything
我们会获取构造方法，有一个cpp文件，这里我不会实现任何东西
so we'll grab the constructor, we do have a cpp files, I'm not gonna implement anything here
构造方法和析构方法，我不需要标记这是虚函数或类似的东西
constructor and destructor like this, I don't need to mark this is virtual or anything like that
因为这个是基类，我们肯定不会发送这个类
because the base class is, and we're certainly not going to be sending this class
这就是为什么我没有把这些方法标记为虚函数
which is why I'm not marking these methods as virtual either
那么我们将有一个OnUpdate(float deltaTime) override
so we'll have OnUpdate for deltaTime override
OnRender和OnImGuiRender，我喜欢那样，好了
OnRender and OnImGuiRender around over, I like that, okay
很好，看起来不错，现在我要打开cpp文件了
cool, looks pretty good to me, now I'm gonna pop over to my cpp file
确保我有那个命名空间test，然后如果我回去，使用VA
make sure I get that namespace test in there, and then if I go back, using visual assist
我可以右键单击该类并创建方法实现
I could just right click on the class and create the method implementations
这是我的cpp文件中最后一次记录，就那样，好了
which is last the trade all been really quickly in my cpp file, just like that, okay
那么我们来建立这个测试，以及想想我们需要什么
so let's actually set up this test and think about what we need
因为我们确实需要一些东西，实际的颜色需要以某种方式存储
because we do need some things, the actual color needs to be stored somehow
所以我要存储这个，把它设为浮点数组
so I am going to store this, I'm just gonna make it a float array
所以我将它命名为float m_Color，并且我知道我现在想要四个这样的
so I'll just call it float m_Color and I know I want four of them like that now
所以4个浮点数就是我们的m_ClearColor
so four floats are going to be our ClearColor
我实际上在构造函数中调用了clearColor
and I actually call a clearColor in the constructor here
我要初始化它，所以clearColor是这样的
I'm going to initialize that, so clearColor to something like
我想我们应该用黑色，但那太无聊了，所以我可以用洋红色之类的
I guess we should probably do black, but that's boring, so I might just make it like magenta or something
所以就是1, 0，实际上就让我们把它写成漂亮的蓝色
so 1 0 actually let's make it like a nice kind of blue
红色是0.2，绿色是0.3，蓝色是0.8，透明度是1
0.2 for red, 0.3 for green, 0.8 for blue and we'll go with 1 for alpha
很好，这是渲染中设置的clearColor
okay, cool, so there's our clearColor set up inside on render
我要使用GLCall glClearColor，它将那个clearColor设置为clearColor
I want to do my GLCall glClearColor, which sets that clearColor to ClearColor
0, 1, 2, 3，就像你们想的那样
zero one two and three as you might expect just like this
然后我们用GLCall(glClear(GL_COLOR_BUFFER_BIT))
and then we'll call glClear with the GL_COLOR_BUFFER_BIT
我的意思是任何一种深度缓冲东西
and I mean for any kind of depth buffer stuff here
实际上，我将包含GL/glew.h来获得所有原始的东西
I will include GL/glew.h to get all the original stuff in in fact
也许我可以只包含Renderer.h，现在可能不需要包含它
maybe I can just include the Renderer, probably don't need to include that now
我们的src目录实际上不在include目录中
our src directory isn't actually in our include directory
那么让我们来设置一下，点击这里的属性
so let's set that up, I'm gonna click on the properties over here
我将src作为包含目录添加到我的C/C++通用附加目录中
I'm just gonna add src as an include directory into my C/C++ general additional
附加目录包括所有配置
additional include directories like that for all configurations
这样我们就可以像这样包含Renderer了
that way we can just include Renderer like this
一切都会好起来的，这就是我相信我们的
and everything will be fine, that that's the kind of stuff that contains, I believe our
是的，这包含了两个glew，而且它应该有GLCall宏
yeah that includes glues within two include glew, and also it should have the GLCall macros
很好，那么继续，这就是点击渲染
okay, brilliant, so there we go, there's a click color rendering
差不多了，我的意思是我不需要销毁任何东西
that's pretty much it, I mean I don't need to destroy anything
我们在这里分配的唯一的东西是一个数组，它还是在堆栈上
with the only thing we actually allocated here was just an array that is again on the stack
所以我们不需要担心人工破坏它
so we don't need to worry about destroying that manually
我觉得其他的都很好
and everything else I think is fine
让我们折叠这些不需要的OnUpdate和OnImGuiRender，马上设置那个
let's collapse these we don't need OnUpdate and OnImGuiRender, we'll set that up in a minute
因为实际上我想现在就把它设置好
because I actually do want to it probably should set that up now
所以如果我们包含ImGui，只要包含imgui/imgui.h
so if we go to, if we include ImGui, just include imgui/imgui.h
然后我们可以做ImGui::Color4，那么是ColorEdit4或者ColorPicker4
then we can just do ImGui, Color4, so ColorEdit4 or ColorPicker4
我不知道不同的是，ColorEdit的区别是什么
I don't know what the difference is, what is the difference ColorEdit
ColorEdit功能有个预览颜色的小方块
the ColorEdit functions have a little colored preview square
好了，ColorEdit可能是我们想要的，就是ColorEdit4
okay, so ColorEdit is probably what we want, ColorEdit4
我们会使用clear color的标签，然后我们会传入m_ClearColor的指针
and we'll just do clear color's label, and then we'll just pass in that m_ClearColor pointer
好了，那就是我们需要做的，非常非常简单的事情
and there we go, that's what we need to do, really really simple stuff
现在我们应该可以看到清除颜色，也可以编辑，那是我的测试
and now we should be able to see our clear color and also edited, that's my test
你们可以明白我所说的建立测试框架的意思
you can see kind of what I mean by setting up a test framework
很容易看到初始化和析构过程中发生了什么
it's so easy to see kind of what happens in the initialization, the destruction
然后真正的渲染它，它真的很干净
and then actually rendering it, it's really clean
保持一切，孤立一切，除非我们测试一切
keeps everything un isolated and separate unless us test everything
这是我们想要的很简单的方式，很好，现在我们来看一个应用
really easily the way that we actually want to, okay, cool, so now if we go into an application
这些东西我已经不需要了
there's all this stuff that I don't care about anymore
所以我要做的就是移除这些
so what I'm actually going to do is just remove this
这是反向控制，所以我不需要担心
it is inversion control, so I don't need to worry about
你们知道的，丢了代码，然后就还原不回来了
you know, losing any code and then not getting it back
因此，如果我想要还原，我总是可以还原的
therefore if I want it back, I can always get it back
那么就在这儿，让我们把这些代码都删除吧
so let's just go over here and remove all of this code
在这里，我把注释也移除了
almost going to go into here, and I'll drag this comment out as well
并且基本上就是去掉所有东西，好了，那么我们不知道要去掉哪些
and basically just remove everything, okay, so we don't know
但我们肯定想保持像ImGui的初始化，渲染的初始化
we definitely want to keep like the ImGui initialization, the render initialization
但其他类似这样的东西都可以去掉了
but everything else like this stuff can just go away
我们也会继续启用混合，好了，很好，所以现在非常非常简单
we'll keep blending on as well, and there we go, okay, cool, so really really simple now
我将去掉所有这些注释，因为这些东西的作用是很明显的，不管如何
I'll get rid of all these comments, because it's pretty obvious what the stuff does, anyway
现在我们来设置一下测试，那么作为一个简单的例子，来测试一下
and now let's set up our test, so as an easy example, just to test this out
我首先要去包含，让我们包含我们的测试，tests/TestClearColor.h
I can include first of all, let's just include our test, tests/TestClearColor.h
如果我到下面这里，我将创建一个TestClearColor test
and if I go down here, I'm just going to make a TestClearColor test
糟糕，我把它放在测试命名空间中了，像那样
oops, I put that in the test namespace like that
我可以使用命名空间，但我现在不打算这么做
I could using the namespace, but I'm not going to at this point
我们会渲染实际的测试，我们会在更新时暂时用0来做
we're going to render the actual test that we'll do on update with delta time zero for now
因为没有任何设置，我们调用onRender
because we don't have anything that set up, we'll do it onRender
然后一旦我们真正启动ImGui框架
and then once we actually start the ImGui frame
我们就会像那样调用test.OnImGuiRender，好了
we're going to do a test.OnImGuiRender like that, okay
看起来不错，按f5，看看会发生什么，好了，那么看看这个
looks pretty good to me, let's just hit f5 and see what happens, okay, so check this out
我们这里有非常漂亮的蓝色，我们已经得到了ImGui的东西
we have that really nice blue color here, we've got our ImGui stuff
我稍微调整一下大小，然后你们就可以看到这是我们的清除颜色
I'm just gonna resize this a little bit, you can see that's our clear color
那就是它的设置，我可以通过这样来调整它
that's what it's set to, I can adjust it just by doing this
我还可以用拾色器，把它变成我想要的任何颜色
I can also bring up a color picker, and actually change it to any color I want
并且正如你们在这里看到的，实际上它改变了背景的颜色
and as you can see here, it actually changes the color of the background
因为那就是我们设置的清除颜色，所以你们可以看到这有多酷，酷
because that's what our clear color is set to, so you can see how cool that is, cool
所以不管怎样，那就是我建立这些测试框架的基础
so anyway, that's the basis of how I want to set up all this test framework stuff
下期我要做的是，设置一个菜单
now what I'm going to do next time, in the next episode is actually set up a menu
这样就不用直接打开一个测试了
so that instead of opening a test straight away
我们也可以使用一些可能很暴力的命令行参数
which we could also have the ability of doing potentially violent command, line argument
或者别的什么，但一般来说，不是清除颜色测试之类的
or something but in general instead of opening just a clear color test or whatever
我实际上想要打开一个菜单，在其中我可以选择任何数量的测试
straight away I actually want to open a menu in which I can select from any number of tests
然后当我点击一个测试，它实际上就会创建并打开它
and then when I click on a test, it actually creates it and opens it
如果我毁了它，或者我从菜单上退出
and if I destroy it, or if I go back from that menu
所以我们会添加一个返回按钮或返回按钮之类的
so we'll add like a little back button or a return button or something
就像那样，这是个错误，如果我们点击那个在清除颜色测试中
like that and just an error, if we click that and where in the clear color test
例如，它应该销毁它，比如完全删除那个对象上那个类的实例
for example it should destroy that like completely delete that instance of that class on that object
回到我们的测试菜单，我们可以选择其他东西，那就是我们的计划
and go back to our test menu, where we can pick something else, so that's the plan
现在我想让你们做的家庭作业是给你们布置一些家庭作业
now what I want you guys to do for homework here we go is giving you guys a bit of a homework task
试着自己实现它，做一个测试菜单，不止一个测试
try and implement that yourselves, go ahead and make a test menu, make more than just one test
我刚刚做了一个清除颜色测试，你们应该做的是回顾之前所有的
I've just made a clear color test, what you should do is go back through all the episodes
看看你们能不能做一个类似纹理的测试
and see if you can make a test for like textures
或者只是符合你们可以自定义的某个顶点颜色
or just accord with a certain vertex color which you can customize
或者你们也可以定制一个统一变量
or maybe accord with a uniform that you can customize as well
使用ImGui完成所有这些测试，并将它们添加到测试菜单中
using ImGui make all of these tests, add them to a test menu
然后在下方评论或discord.com上分享你的解决方案
and then share your solution in the comments below or on discord.com
如果你们访问TheCherno.com/discord，就可以加入我的discord服务
so if you go to TheCherno.com/discord, you can join my discord server
有一个OpenGL，不，有一个图形频道，你们可以在那里讨论这些东西
there's an OpenGL, no, there's a graphics channel, where you can talk about stuff like this
在那里分享你们的解决方案，是的，你们自己去尝试一下那个吧
and share your solutions there, and yeah just have a go with doing that yourselves
下周我会给你们看我的解决方案，无论下一期会做什么
and then I'll show you my solution next week on in whatever the next episode ends up coming out
所以不论如何，我希望你们喜欢这个视频
so anyway anyway, I hope you guys enjoyed this video
如果你们确实喜欢的话，那就为这个视频点赞吧
if you did do, you hit that like button
你们也可以通过访问patreon.com/TheCherno来支持这个系列教程
you're gonna you can help support the series by going to patreon.com/TheCherno
和往常一样，所有的源代码都被上传到github存储库
as always all of the source code is uploaded onto a github repository
如果你们支持这个系列，就可以去访问那个
which you get access to, if you support the series
所以一定要去看看，并且你们也会得到一堆其他很酷的奖励
so definitely check that out, and also you'll get a bunch of other cool rewards
和往常一样，非常感谢我所有可爱的支持者，让这个系列成为可能
and as always huge thank you to all of my lovely supporters to make this series possible
从现在开始，我将优先考虑这个系列，而不是c++系列
I'm going to prioritize this series from now on over the c++ series
因为已经在c++系列中涵盖了很多东西，而OpenGL系列则有所欠缺
because we've covered a lot of stuff in the c++ series, and the OpenGL series is kind of lacking
那么下周我们会讲完这个测试的内容，然后再下一周或者再下一期
so next week we're going to finish off this Test stuff, and then the week after that or the episode after that
也许我甚至会一周做好几期，谁知道呢，但愿我是这样希望的
maybe I'll even do multiple episodes of week, who knows, hopefully I'm hoping
我们将继续做批渲染
we will move on to doing the batch renderer
最后是3D的东西，所以我对这个系列的未来感到非常兴奋
and then 3D stuff eventually, so yeah, I'm really excited for the future of the series
希望大家喜欢这个视频，下次见，再见
I hope you guys enjoyed the video, I'll see you next time, goodbye